<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Power Platform on Burgers &amp; Bytes</title>
    <link>//aseURL:1313/tags/power-platform/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Power Platform on Burgers &amp; Bytes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="//aseURL:1313/tags/power-platform/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>European BizApps Summit; My top 3 and some more...</title>
      <link>//aseURL:1313/blog/20250601-bizappssummit2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//aseURL:1313/blog/20250601-bizappssummit2025/</guid>
      <description>Two years ago where it all started at the European Collaboration Summit 2023 I started my first blog&#xD;.&#xA;Next to I added something to my bucket list: presenting on the event myself, just as a personal challenge.&#xA;Fast forward to now: this blog is the result of both goals in action. Last week, I got to speak at European BizApps Summit 2025 together with Albert-Jan Schot.&#xA;Keynote and sessions Marco Casalaina kicked things off during keynote with cool demos.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>💡From business case to business value with the Power Platform</title>
      <link>//aseURL:1313/blog/20250512-businesscasebusinessvalue/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 May 2025 00:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//aseURL:1313/blog/20250512-businesscasebusinessvalue/</guid>
      <description>Power Platform adoption doesn’t start with a full-fledged governance strategy—it starts when people begin experimenting. Even before you’ve set up a Landing Zone or Center of Excellence, there’s often already momentum. That’s a great thing.&#xA;But inspiration alone isn’t enough. What many organizations miss is giving employees a path from idea to implementation. That means making it easy to propose, shape, and justify a solution. And that’s where a simple business case one-pager comes in.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>💥From idea to impact: kickstarting Power Platform adoption</title>
      <link>//aseURL:1313/blog/20250512-adoptionbusinessvalue/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 May 2025 00:00:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//aseURL:1313/blog/20250512-adoptionbusinessvalue/</guid>
      <description>Power Platform adoption starts with building the business case There are plenty of opportunities to add value with the Power Platform. And interestingly, user adoption often begins even before anything is officially in place.&#xA;As an introduction to the Power Platform, organizations can offer anything from “App in a Day” workshops and lunch-and-learn sessions to learning pages on the intranet—anything that inspires employees. Fantastic! But what’s often overlooked is that concepts and ideas gets lost.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A solid foundation of the Power Platform</title>
      <link>//aseURL:1313/blog/20240325-solidfoundationpowerplatform/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//aseURL:1313/blog/20240325-solidfoundationpowerplatform/</guid>
      <description>In today&amp;rsquo;s rapidly evolving digital landscape, organizations often find themselves relying on outdated Excel-based processes, which pose significant risks. However, with the emergence of the Power Platform, a revolutionary low-code development platform, there is a transformative solution at hand. This blog explores the potential of the Power Platform in streamlining operations, mitigating risks, and empowering employees to become citizen developers.&#xA;Source https://dilbert.com/strip/2007-08-08&#xD;Excel as business critical When people ask what exactly you can do with Power Platform, we often make comparisons with what people used to make in Excel.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>European Collaboration Summit 2023; My top 3 and some more...</title>
      <link>//aseURL:1313/blog/20230525-collaborationsummit2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//aseURL:1313/blog/20230525-collaborationsummit2023/</guid>
      <description>My report from the European Collaboration Summit 2023&#xA;It had been in my calendar since last October, on 22 May it was finally there: the European Collaboration Summit! In this blog, I am happy to share my personal top 3. Plenty to choose from, so in addition to a nice top 3, I also added an unmissable encore.&#xA;Within Power Platform projects, it is necessary to think carefully about the architecture.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
