<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Center of Excellence on Burgers &amp; Bytes</title>
    <link>//aseURL:1313/tags/center-of-excellence/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Center of Excellence on Burgers &amp; Bytes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="//aseURL:1313/tags/center-of-excellence/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A solid foundation of the Power Platform</title>
      <link>//aseURL:1313/blog/20240325-solidfoundationpowerplatform/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//aseURL:1313/blog/20240325-solidfoundationpowerplatform/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In today&amp;rsquo;s rapidly evolving digital landscape, organizations often find themselves relying on outdated Excel-based processes, which pose significant risks. However, with the emergence of the Power Platform, a revolutionary low-code development platform, there is a transformative solution at hand. This blog explores the potential of the Power Platform in streamlining operations, mitigating risks, and empowering employees to become citizen developers.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//aseURL:1313/images/20240325SolidFoundation/1-Dilbert.png&#34; alt=&#34;Dilbert&#34;&gt;&#xA;Source &lt;a href=&#34;https://dilbert.com/strip/2007-08-08&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://dilbert.com/strip/2007-08-08&lt;/a&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;excel-as-business-critical&#34;&gt;Excel as business critical&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When people ask what exactly you can do with Power Platform, we often make comparisons with what people used to make in Excel. Well, &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;used to be&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt; I wish I could say. We still come across it, business-critical processes that rely entirely on an Excel with all sorts of formulas. Employees creating complex formulas and macros. Still, a big risk for an organization. Management is not regulated, what if someone accidentally adjusts a formula, who notices? A risk that is not always recognised because &amp;lsquo;it has been like this for years and it has never gone wrong&amp;rsquo;. So the moment it goes wrong, it goes badly wrong. The need for change is evident, and the Power Platform offers a promising way forward.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
