<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Power Automate on Burgers &amp; Bytes</title>
    <link>//aseURL:1313/tags/power-automate/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Power Automate on Burgers &amp; Bytes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="//aseURL:1313/tags/power-automate/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Color = context. Work smarter, avoid mistakes</title>
      <link>//aseURL:1313/blog/20251003-environmentswitchcolor/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//aseURL:1313/blog/20251003-environmentswitchcolor/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ever clicked in your app and wondered: &lt;em&gt;Am I in DEV or PRD now?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Mistakes happen. Mis-clicks happen. And worst case: you update data in the wrong environment.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this blog: a simple pattern to make your app &lt;em&gt;visually aware&lt;/em&gt; — based on environment.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;-the-idea-in-short&#34;&gt;🎯 The idea in short&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Create an &lt;strong&gt;environment variable&lt;/strong&gt; (e.g. &lt;code&gt;CurrentEnvironment&lt;/code&gt;) with possible values &lt;code&gt;DEV&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;ACC&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;PRD&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;In your app, use logic to pick a &lt;strong&gt;color&lt;/strong&gt; based on that value&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Result: the UI itself signals &lt;em&gt;which environment you’re in&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Color = Context. Work smarter, avoid mistakes.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Export Dataverse data to Excel triggered from Canvas app</title>
      <link>//aseURL:1313/blog/20250912-exporttoexcel/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//aseURL:1313/blog/20250912-exporttoexcel/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;//aseURL:1313/blog/20240325-solidfoundationpowerplatform/&#34;&gt;Over a year ago I already wrote&lt;/a&gt;&#xD;&#xA; stated something we jokingly say: “What is the most frequently used functionality of an ERP system?”, with as the answer: “…the export to Excel”.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It is still an often request, which is there by default while creating a Model Driven app, while end-users often would like to export data in a Canvas app as well. This blog describes how to create a Power Automate flow which you can trigger via Canvas app to export the data from Dataverse into Excel.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Manipulate JSON objects or arrays: using setProperty/addProperty</title>
      <link>//aseURL:1313/blog/20250823-jsonmanipulationpowerautomate/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//aseURL:1313/blog/20250823-jsonmanipulationpowerautomate/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In Power Automate, working with JSON objects and arrays is essential for building &lt;strong&gt;advanced, scalable, and maintainable flows&lt;/strong&gt;. JSON acts as the backbone of data exchange, allowing you to represent structured information flexibly.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Two powerful expressions—&lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;setProperty()&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;addProperty()&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;—unlock the ability to &lt;strong&gt;dynamically update, expand, and manipulate JSON objects&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This article explores what these functions do, why they matter, and how you can apply them in real-world automation scenarios.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-manipulate-json-in-power-automate&#34;&gt;Why Manipulate JSON in Power Automate?&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Before diving into the syntax, let’s answer the bigger question: &lt;em&gt;why bother manipulating JSON at all?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Price winning solution: AI-Driven archiving of SharePoint Sites</title>
      <link>//aseURL:1313/blog/20250325-powerfuldevshacktogether/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//aseURL:1313/blog/20250325-powerfuldevshacktogether/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A very special blog this time! Together with my teammembers from Blis Digital we participated in the Powerful Devs Hack 2025. This hackathon  was organized by Microsoft and could shortly described by:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s time to start developing secure solutions at enterprise scale using the power of AI and the Power Platform! 🤖 + 📚 = 🔥&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There were different categories to participate in and all projects were evaluated by a panel of judges against technologies and languages, using the following aspects:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Provision SharePoint agents using Power Automate</title>
      <link>//aseURL:1313/blog/20250303-provisionsharepointagent/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//aseURL:1313/blog/20250303-provisionsharepointagent/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;scenario&#34;&gt;Scenario&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;On a SharePoint front page or document library you can create a SharePoint agent. Totally fine for just creating a couple, but what if the scenario requires the same SharePoint agent setup on a lot of sites.&#xA;In that case you would automatically want to provision those agents. This way you can immediately impact the behavior, change the default of the welcome message, starter prompts and instructions for the agent. This blog describes how this can be achieved using Power Automate Flow.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Improving performance insights using Apdex</title>
      <link>//aseURL:1313/blog/20250211-powerautomateapdexscore/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//aseURL:1313/blog/20250211-powerautomateapdexscore/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;scenario&#34;&gt;Scenario&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ever heard users complain about the sluggishness of your Power Automate flow? But how do we know if that complaint is based on actual performance or just a feeling?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this blog, we’ll explore how to move from subjective complaints to objective insights by using &lt;strong&gt;Apdex scores&lt;/strong&gt; to evaluate Power Automate flow performance.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-apdex-and-how-does-it-help-in-measuring-flow-performance&#34;&gt;What is Apdex and how does it help in measuring flow performance?&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;apdex-overview&#34;&gt;Apdex Overview&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.apdex.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Apdex (Application Performance Index)&lt;/a&gt;&#xD;&#xA; is a standardized way of measuring user satisfaction with application performance. It uses a scoring system that tracks how long it takes for a flow to respond, translating that into a more user-experience-oriented metric.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dynamically show/hide elements in Adaptive Cards</title>
      <link>//aseURL:1313/blog/20241108-adaptivecarddynamicshowhide/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//aseURL:1313/blog/20241108-adaptivecarddynamicshowhide/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It took me hours to figure this out, so here&amp;rsquo;s to saving you time!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;After spending hours trying to figure this out, I figured it’s time to write it down. Hopefully, this post will save you some time and frustration, so you don’t have to go through the same process I did!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;designing-an-adaptive-card&#34;&gt;Designing an Adaptive Card&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Designing an Adaptive Card using the &lt;a href=&#34;https://adaptivecards.io/designer/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Adaptive Cards Designer&lt;/a&gt;&#xD;&#xA; is surprisingly easy. You can create interactive cards with just a few clicks!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Power Apps: Transpose Excel Data using Power Fx</title>
      <link>//aseURL:1313/blog/20240522-powerfxtransposeexcel/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//aseURL:1313/blog/20240522-powerfxtransposeexcel/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A lot of business processes are supported by data stored in Excel sheets.&#xA;Working with Power Apps often eliminates the use of an Excel sheet, but in some cases the data needs to be stored into an Excel sheet.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this blog the concept of transposing the data from an Excel table will be described, so you can use this data throughout the app.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;scenario&#34;&gt;Scenario&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As an input there is an Excel table in which there are multiple rows and multiple columns. The first column has the Country value in it and the other columns describes the products of that Country.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Using Microsoft Graph and Power Automate to post an Announcement Message in Teams channel</title>
      <link>//aseURL:1313/blog/20240212teamsannouncementmessage/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//aseURL:1313/blog/20240212teamsannouncementmessage/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;scenario&#34;&gt;Scenario&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This blog describes the Flow to create a Team and start with a message of type Announcement.&#xA;The default &amp;lsquo;Post a message in a chat or channel&amp;rsquo; isn&amp;rsquo;t sufficient, because the message type can&amp;rsquo;t be selected, so it can&amp;rsquo;t be an Announcement.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The end result should be a clear message in a Teams channel:&#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;//aseURL:1313/images/20240212TeamsAnnouncementMessage/1-Announcementbanner.png&#34; alt=&#34;Announcement&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;flow-actions-to-create-team&#34;&gt;Flow actions to create Team&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In order to share the full story the Team needs to be created and Team ID and Channel ID needs to be stored in a variable.&#xA;To read the details collapse these steps below:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Part 3: Enhancing User Engagement Measurement on SharePoint Intranets: Visualize data</title>
      <link>//aseURL:1313/blog/20231021-userengagement-part3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Oct 2023 00:00:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//aseURL:1313/blog/20231021-userengagement-part3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Measuring user engagement is crucial for any SharePoint-based intranet to ensure that the platform is meeting its intended purpose and delivering value to the users. You can already benefit from Viva Connections and Viva Insights to enhance the user engagement measurement capabilities.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;//aseURL:1313/blog/20231021-userengagement-part1&#34;&gt;In the first part of this blog serie&lt;/a&gt;&#xD;&#xA;, you could read how to use the Power Platform to measure user engagement even more deeply using KPI regarding user engagement.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Part 2: Enhancing User Engagement Measurement on SharePoint Intranets: Page Freshness</title>
      <link>//aseURL:1313/blog/20231021-userengagement-part2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Oct 2023 00:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//aseURL:1313/blog/20231021-userengagement-part2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Measuring user engagement is crucial for any SharePoint-based intranet to ensure that the platform is meeting its intended purpose and delivering value to the users. You can already benefit from Viva Connections and Viva Insights to enhance the user engagement measurement capabilities.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;//aseURL:1313/BlogBytes/blog/20231021-userengagement-part1&#34;&gt;In the first part of this blog serie&lt;/a&gt;&#xD;&#xA;, you could read how to use the Power Platform to measure user engagement even more deeply using KPI&amp;rsquo;s regarding user engagement.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Part 1: Enhancing User Engagement Measurement on SharePoint Intranets with Power Platform</title>
      <link>//aseURL:1313/blog/20231021-userengagement-part1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Oct 2023 00:00:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//aseURL:1313/blog/20231021-userengagement-part1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Measuring user engagement is crucial for any SharePoint-based intranet to ensure that the platform is meeting its intended purpose and delivering value to the users. You can already benefit from Viva Connections and Viva Insights to enhance the user engagement measurement capabilities.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the first part of this blog serie, we will explore how to use the Power Platform to measure user engagement even more deeply using KPI&amp;rsquo;s regarding user engagement.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Make use of the responses: display the survey data of the Forms - part 3</title>
      <link>//aseURL:1313/blog/msforms-part3-dashboard/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Aug 2023 00:00:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//aseURL:1313/blog/msforms-part3-dashboard/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This blog is part of the blog series for Microsoft Forms automation to create automatic update of you question of the week on your SharePoint intranet.&#xA;The first blog explains &lt;a href=&#34;//aseURL:1313/blog/msforms-part1-customconnector/&#34;&gt;how to create a custom connector using the undocumented Microsoft Forms API&lt;/a&gt;&#xD;&#xA;.&#xA;The second blog describes how to &lt;a href=&#34;//aseURL:1313/blog/msforms-part2-questionoftheweek/&#34;&gt;keep your ‘Question of the week’ based on Microsoft Forms up-to-date&lt;/a&gt;&#xD;&#xA;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The result of the first two parts of this blog series is a nice looking SharePoint list which contains all data from the Question of the week.&#xA;Not only the answer options that could be given, but the results of those questions as well.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft Forms automation: update Forms poll on SharePoint intranet - part 2</title>
      <link>//aseURL:1313/blog/msforms-part2-questionoftheweek/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Aug 2023 00:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//aseURL:1313/blog/msforms-part2-questionoftheweek/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Creating a social intranet that fosters collaboration and engagement among employees is essential in today&amp;rsquo;s digital workplace. One effective component of a social intranet is a &amp;ldquo;question of the week&amp;rdquo; or poll functionality. While SharePoint doesn&amp;rsquo;t have a built-in poll feature, you can use a Microsoft Form with one question to achieve the same effect. However, updating the question weekly can be a manual and time-consuming task.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, Microsoft doesn&amp;rsquo;t provide a standard API for Microsoft Forms that can easily be integrated with Power Automate to automate question creation and management of a Form. In the first part of this blog series there is explained how to create a custom connector for Microsoft Forms. This custom connector with related actions will be used in this blog.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft Forms automation: a custom connector - part 1</title>
      <link>//aseURL:1313/blog/msforms-part1-customconnector/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Aug 2023 00:00:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//aseURL:1313/blog/msforms-part1-customconnector/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Creating a social intranet that fosters collaboration and engagement among employees is essential in today&amp;rsquo;s digital workplace. One effective component of a social intranet is a &amp;ldquo;question of the week&amp;rdquo; or poll functionality. While SharePoint doesn&amp;rsquo;t have a built-in poll feature, you can use a Microsoft Form with one question to achieve the same effect. However, updating the question weekly can be a manual and time-consuming task.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, Microsoft doesn&amp;rsquo;t provide a standard API for Microsoft Forms that can easily be integrated with Power Automate to automate question creation and management of a Form. But don&amp;rsquo;t worry! In this blog, we&amp;rsquo;ll explore creative ways to make use of the undocumented Microsoft Forms API and Power Automate to automate the process of updating the question every week.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Power Apps Canvas: one icon with eleven color variations</title>
      <link>//aseURL:1313/blog/20230805powerappiconcolorvariations/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//aseURL:1313/blog/20230805powerappiconcolorvariations/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;situation&#34;&gt;Situation&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the Netherlands, the energy label of houses is indicated by a letter and a corresponding color. Today, we have 11 different labels, &lt;a href=&#34;https://woonbewust.nl/energielabel-woningen&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;ranging from A++++ to G&lt;/a&gt;&#xD;&#xA;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This label is usually indicated by a pentagonal arrow, containing the letter and corresponding color. An example:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//aseURL:1313/images/20230805PowerAppIconColorVariations/1-Example.png&#34; alt=&#34;Example&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.homekeur.nl/energielabel-woning-uitleg/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://www.homekeur.nl/energielabel-woning-uitleg/&lt;/a&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;scenario&#34;&gt;Scenario&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In a Canvas Power App, the letter could be selected in the dropdown and icon and its corresponding label should be displayed based on the selected value.&#xA;The end result:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to get all SharePoint sites of a hub site in Power Automate</title>
      <link>//aseURL:1313/blog/20230722-sharepointgetallhubsites/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//aseURL:1313/blog/20230722-sharepointgetallhubsites/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-challenge&#34;&gt;The Challenge&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There is a lot of information available on how to retrieve all sites related to a SharePoint hub using Powershell.&#xA;Another option is to use Microsoft Graph and search for all sites.&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;https://graph.microsoft.com/v1.0/sites?search=&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://graph.microsoft.com/v1.0/sites?search=&lt;/a&gt;&#xD;&#xA;*&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//aseURL:1313/images/20230722SharePointGetAllHubsites/1-Graph.png&#34; alt=&#34;Graph&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The challenge was to get all the sites of a hub in Power Automate without using premium actions like the HTTP request.&#xA;This blog describes how to achieve this!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;needed-http-requests&#34;&gt;Needed HTTP requests&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Initialized a variable to store the URL of the hubsite. Next step is to get the HubSiteID. You can get the ID using the:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to create a markdown table with flexible amount of rows in an Approval</title>
      <link>//aseURL:1313/blog/20230721-approvalmdtablerows/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//aseURL:1313/blog/20230721-approvalmdtablerows/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Approval functionality is really powerful! A lot of situation requires a response like an approval. The approval action in Power Automate does have some parameters which you can enter data in. Next to required details like the ‘Approval type’, ‘Title’ and ‘Assigned to’, you can enter Details. For Details you can use markdown to design the setup.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-challenge&#34;&gt;The challenge&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this blog the challenge that’s got resolved is that the approval request contains a table which as multiple rows, but the amount of rows are flexible and different every flow run.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
