<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Pages on Burgers &amp; Bytes</title>
    <link>//aseURL:1313/page/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Pages on Burgers &amp; Bytes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="//aseURL:1313/page/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft Forms API</title>
      <link>//aseURL:1313/page/msformapi/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//aseURL:1313/page/msformapi/</guid>
      <description>Every question type has is own setup of the body content.&#xA;Body content The payload of the different question types all have the same parameters:&#xA;questionInfo type title id order isQuiz required { &amp;#34;questionInfo&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;type&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;title&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;Question&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;id&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;order&amp;#34;: 4000500, &amp;#34;isQuiz&amp;#34;: false, &amp;#34;required&amp;#34;: false } Parameter type Question Type Choice Question.Choice Text Question.TextField Rating Question.Rating Date Question.DateTime Ranking Question.Ranking Likert Question.Matrix Upload File Question.FileUpload Net Promoter Score Question.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spotlight</title>
      <link>//aseURL:1313/page/spotlight/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//aseURL:1313/page/spotlight/</guid>
      <description>Below a list of my recent and upcoming events:&#xA;2025-12-03 - ESPC25 Dublin - Automated testing in the Power Platform: matching governance, upholding quality, compliance and efficiency (together with Arjan Rijsdijk) A session regarding how testing and governance go hand-in-hand and share practical tips for testing Power Apps Canvas and Power Automate.&#xA;2025-06-21 - CollabDays Netherlands - Unlocking Dataverse Functions: code less, do more! This session explores Dataverse Functions and triggers (formerly low-code plugins), a powerful tool for building logic in apps and workflows with minimal code.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>//aseURL:1313/page/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//aseURL:1313/page/about/</guid>
      <description>My name is Elianne and I am a Power Platform Consultant at Blis Digital&#xD;in Barendrecht, The Netherlands. Since 2016 I obtained several Microsoft certifications: full transcript can be found on my Microsoft Learn profile.&#xD;I love to gain more knowledge and expertise by going to different user groups and conferences myself, but I also like to share knowledge in different ways: by writing blogs, giving presentations, guest lectures at an university of applied science and app-in-a-day workshops.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
