<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Governance on Burgers &amp; Bytes</title>
    <link>//aseURL:1313/tags/governance/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Governance on Burgers &amp; Bytes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 27 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="//aseURL:1313/tags/governance/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>🎯 From idea to action: smart prioritization with business value analysis</title>
      <link>//aseURL:1313/blog/20250927-businesscasematrix/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//aseURL:1313/blog/20250927-businesscasematrix/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Power Platform adoption isn&amp;rsquo;t just about collecting ideas: it&amp;rsquo;s about choosing the right ideas. And that&amp;rsquo;s where many organizations get stuck.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;After setting up a &lt;a href=&#34;//aseURL:1313/blog/20250512-adoptionbusinessvalue/&#34;&gt;clear submission process&lt;/a&gt;&#xD;&#xA; and using a &lt;a href=&#34;//aseURL:1313/blog/20250512-businesscasebusinessvalue/&#34;&gt;structured business case&lt;/a&gt;&#xD;&#xA;, the next challenge emerges: &lt;strong&gt;Which ideas do you tackle first?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-problem-too-many-good-ideas&#34;&gt;The problem: too many good ideas&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;💡&lt;strong&gt;A good idea isn&amp;rsquo;t necessarily a good plan.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;With the Power Platform, you can build something incredibly fast. And that makes it tempting to just start. Quickly create an app, click together a flow&amp;hellip; done!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>💡From business case to business value with the Power Platform</title>
      <link>//aseURL:1313/blog/20250512-businesscasebusinessvalue/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 May 2025 00:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//aseURL:1313/blog/20250512-businesscasebusinessvalue/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Power Platform adoption doesn’t start with a full-fledged governance strategy—it starts when people begin experimenting. Even before you’ve set up a Landing Zone or Center of Excellence, there’s often already momentum. That’s a great thing.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;But inspiration alone isn’t enough. What many organizations miss is giving employees a path from idea to implementation. That means making it easy to propose, shape, and justify a solution. And that’s where a simple &lt;strong&gt;business case one-pager&lt;/strong&gt; comes in.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>💥From idea to impact: kickstarting Power Platform adoption</title>
      <link>//aseURL:1313/blog/20250512-adoptionbusinessvalue/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 May 2025 00:00:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//aseURL:1313/blog/20250512-adoptionbusinessvalue/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;power-platform-adoption-starts-with-building-the-business-case&#34;&gt;Power Platform adoption starts with building the business case&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There are plenty of opportunities to add value with the Power Platform. And interestingly, user adoption often begins even before anything is officially in place.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As an introduction to the Power Platform, organizations can offer anything from “App in a Day” workshops and lunch-and-learn sessions to learning pages on the intranet—anything that inspires employees. Fantastic! But what’s often overlooked is that concepts and ideas gets lost. So, give employees a clear path from experimentation to real results.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A solid foundation of the Power Platform</title>
      <link>//aseURL:1313/blog/20240325-solidfoundationpowerplatform/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//aseURL:1313/blog/20240325-solidfoundationpowerplatform/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In today&amp;rsquo;s rapidly evolving digital landscape, organizations often find themselves relying on outdated Excel-based processes, which pose significant risks. However, with the emergence of the Power Platform, a revolutionary low-code development platform, there is a transformative solution at hand. This blog explores the potential of the Power Platform in streamlining operations, mitigating risks, and empowering employees to become citizen developers.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//aseURL:1313/images/20240325SolidFoundation/1-Dilbert.png&#34; alt=&#34;Dilbert&#34;&gt;&#xA;Source &lt;a href=&#34;https://dilbert.com/strip/2007-08-08&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://dilbert.com/strip/2007-08-08&lt;/a&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;excel-as-business-critical&#34;&gt;Excel as business critical&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When people ask what exactly you can do with Power Platform, we often make comparisons with what people used to make in Excel. Well, &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;used to be&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt; I wish I could say. We still come across it, business-critical processes that rely entirely on an Excel with all sorts of formulas. Employees creating complex formulas and macros. Still, a big risk for an organization. Management is not regulated, what if someone accidentally adjusts a formula, who notices? A risk that is not always recognised because &amp;lsquo;it has been like this for years and it has never gone wrong&amp;rsquo;. So the moment it goes wrong, it goes badly wrong. The need for change is evident, and the Power Platform offers a promising way forward.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Validating Naming Conventions in Power Apps</title>
      <link>//aseURL:1313/blog/20230926-powerappsvalidatingnamingconventions/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Sep 2023 00:00:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//aseURL:1313/blog/20230926-powerappsvalidatingnamingconventions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-naming-conventions&#34;&gt;Why naming conventions&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One of the main advices while creating Power Apps canvas apps is to use proper naming conventions for all the components you&amp;rsquo;re using.&#xA;Not only to support readability for your own usage, also for supportability. Probably it&amp;rsquo;s not too difficult to convince someone of its importance, while in the hustle and bustle of everyday life, you don&amp;rsquo;t give it priority always.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Some advantages:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Consistency&lt;/strong&gt;; so you can better focus on the solution&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Maintainability&lt;/strong&gt;; everyone has the same language and can therefore navigate through a solution more easily&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Interchangeability&lt;/strong&gt;; copying, changing and maintaining solutions can be done by multiple people&#xA;​&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This blog gives and explains a Powershell script which you can use to validate naming convention in your Power App.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
