<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Governance on Burgers &amp; Bytes</title>
    <link>//aseURL:1313/tags/governance/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Governance on Burgers &amp; Bytes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="//aseURL:1313/tags/governance/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>💡From business case to business value with the Power Platform</title>
      <link>//aseURL:1313/blog/20250501-businesscasebusinessvalue/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//aseURL:1313/blog/20250501-businesscasebusinessvalue/</guid>
      <description>Power Platform adoption doesn’t start with a full-fledged governance strategy—it starts when people begin experimenting. Even before you’ve set up a Landing Zone or Center of Excellence, there’s often already momentum. That’s a great thing.&#xA;But inspiration alone isn’t enough. What many organizations miss is giving employees a path from idea to implementation. That means making it easy to propose, shape, and justify a solution. And that’s where a simple business case one-pager comes in.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>💥From idea to impact: kickstarting Power Platform adoption</title>
      <link>//aseURL:1313/blog/20250501-adoptionbusinessvalue/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//aseURL:1313/blog/20250501-adoptionbusinessvalue/</guid>
      <description>Power Platform adoption starts with building the business case There are plenty of opportunities to add value with the Power Platform. And interestingly, user adoption often begins even before anything is officially in place.&#xA;As an introduction to the Power Platform, organizations can offer anything from “App in a Day” workshops and lunch-and-learn sessions to learning pages on the intranet—anything that inspires employees. Fantastic! But what’s often overlooked is that concepts and ideas gets lost.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A solid foundation of the Power Platform</title>
      <link>//aseURL:1313/blog/20240325-solidfoundationpowerplatform/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//aseURL:1313/blog/20240325-solidfoundationpowerplatform/</guid>
      <description>In today&amp;rsquo;s rapidly evolving digital landscape, organizations often find themselves relying on outdated Excel-based processes, which pose significant risks. However, with the emergence of the Power Platform, a revolutionary low-code development platform, there is a transformative solution at hand. This blog explores the potential of the Power Platform in streamlining operations, mitigating risks, and empowering employees to become citizen developers.&#xA;Source https://dilbert.com/strip/2007-08-08&#xD;Excel as business critical When people ask what exactly you can do with Power Platform, we often make comparisons with what people used to make in Excel.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Validating Naming Conventions in Power Apps</title>
      <link>//aseURL:1313/blog/20230926-powerappsvalidatingnamingconventions/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Sep 2023 00:00:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//aseURL:1313/blog/20230926-powerappsvalidatingnamingconventions/</guid>
      <description>Why naming conventions One of the main advices while creating Power Apps canvas apps is to use proper naming conventions for all the components you&amp;rsquo;re using. Not only to support readability for your own usage, also for supportability. Probably it&amp;rsquo;s not too difficult to convince someone of its importance, while in the hustle and bustle of everyday life, you don&amp;rsquo;t give it priority always.&#xA;Some advantages:&#xA;Consistency; so you can better focus on the solution Maintainability; everyone has the same language and can therefore navigate through a solution more easily Interchangeability; copying, changing and maintaining solutions can be done by multiple people ​ This blog gives and explains a Powershell script which you can use to validate naming convention in your Power App.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
